# JOAN WANINI MAINA

Nairobi, Kenya | +254 712 632 595 | joanmaina537@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with over three years of experience in agile software development. I have worked as a software developer and quality assurance team lead within various teams that provided software solutions. Over the years, I keep refining my skills as I learn to improve the software development lifecycle on the scrum teams I work with.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Quality Assurance Team Lead

Griffin Global Technologies | Atlanta, Georgia

October 2023 - Current

- o Test software solutions throughout the software development lifecycle
- o Ensure development team meets clients' requirements
- o Lead team of software testers in test planning and execution
- o Creating reports to track testing progress and results
- o Run performance testing using JMeter to validate API scalability
- o Provide QA signoff on releases
- o Lead and attend various meetings to streamline processes in the company

#### Software Technical Support Analyst

The Jitu | Nyeri, Kenya

January 2022 – October 2023

- o Communicate with client to identify issues faced and seek solutions
- Coordinate with software developers to deliver software solution to client within deadlines
- Monitor systems for failures via running scripts to check data in SQL and logs in AWS Cloudwatch

 Use testing tools such as Cypress for end-to-end testing and Postman for API functional tests

#### Software Developer Intern

The Jitu | Nyeri, Kenya

October 2021 - December 2021

- Develop website systems using MERN stack to solve problems faced in project teams when assigning tasks
- o Collaborate with other developers in development and testing

# **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of science in Compuer Science

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

December 2021

GPA: Second class upper honors

#### Accomplishments:

- Awarded top student in second year of study
- Leart software programming concepts such as object-oriented programming and data structures
- Learnt various programming languages e.g. Java, Python, C and Javascript.

#### Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Moi Girls High School - Isinya

November 2017

Grade: B+ of 69 points

## Accomplishments:

- Awarded top student in Mathematics
- Learnt computer skills, languages and sciences.

#### Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

Bethlehem Academy November 2013

Grade: A- of 395/500 marks

# **SKILLS**

- Strong knowledge of agile software development lifecycle
- Excellent communication skills, both verbal and written
- Attention to detail in software testing
- Ability to collaborate with other software testers, developers and business stakeholders
- Good understanding of software testing and documentation tools

## **TOOLS**

- Programming: Java, Javascript, Python
- Testing: Postman, Cypress, Selenium, Jmeter
- Documentation: Jira, Confluence, Figma, Testrail, Zephyr
- Version Control: Git
- Cloud computation: AWS, Azure
- Data Management: SQL, MongoDB, RDS

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Learning and improving technical and soft skills:

- CSM Scrum Master Certification Complete and got certified by Scrum Alliance in August 2023
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Badge completed AWS Cloud practitioner course and received a badge in June 2023
- Freecodecamp responsive web course completed python scripting course on Freecodecamp in August 2021
- 4. Simplilearn Git and Agile Courses April 2023

Active volunteer in organizations that seek to educate young people on science and technology.

 Apprentice Cloud – Worked with a team of technical mentors to mentor Javascript bootcamp members on full stack development.

- 2. WiSSA Leading a team of web developers to redesign and maintain the organization's website.
- 3. Women Techmakers DeKUT- Create articles and talks to educate people on software testing concepts.

REFEREES – To be provided on request